Whoever gets to the temple first wins.
Why? Aang. No fair.
Let's get him. Come on. Hurry up.
Hi Nema.
Good morning, Aang. Hey.
Oh. Hello, Aang.
Oh, perfect timing.
Mind giving me a lift.
Yo, this isn't the best time.
I'm getting old, you know. My body
doesn't move like it used to.
I'm kind of in the middle of something.
You are so heavy.
Heavy? Me? I eat nothing but vegetables.
Pie is not a vegetable. I'm going to
lose the race.
Race? What race?
Aang as an air bender, it's important
that you know when to show restraint.
Even if you have the power to win, you
are the avatar. A lot of people are
going to rely on you.
Avatar.
He's gone. He ran away.
What? I'm here.
Where's the Avatar?
Avatar.
Hey, where are you?
I'm here.
I'm I'm here. I'm here. I'm here.
Hey, Momo.
Hi, Aang. Was I asleep for long?
Okay. Okay. I'm awake already.
I know. I know. We've got a job to
finish.
Let's continue our journey back to our
old home.
This may not have been our best trip,
but any air bender relic we find makes
it all worthwhile.
This could be the oldest piece in our
collection.
Son,
I miss you.
Momo, go outside with Aang.
Now,
who are you? Why are you doing this?
Please stop. I don't want to hurt you.
Where is it? Where is it? No, that's not
it. Hey, those are antiques.
Enough.
Wait, I found it.
Zuko, right after you.
Wait.
No. That's a thousand years old.
Give it to me.
Why don't we just talk? Maybe I can
help. We don't need your help, Avatar.
We're done living in a world where
benders have all the power and we have
none.
Who are you?
We're the denied.
The denied?
Just kill him already.
No. They'll bring the whole place down.
You saved me.
Grab the map. Let's go.
Oh no.
Oh,
I'm fine, Momo. I'm fine.
Oh, you've got to get to Republic City.
Appa. Yep. Yep.
Water.
Her tribes gather strength from the moon
and flow with the tides.
Earth,
a kingdom of unshakable will, reliable
and strong.
Fire,
a nation capable of great destruction,
but also
of great warmth.
Air. peaceful nomads with the power of a
hurricane, but the spirit of a gentle
breeze.
For generations, the Avatar, the one
master of all four elements, kept the
nations in balance.
But when that responsibility fell to me
as a child, I ran away. I was caught in
a deadly storm. But my Avatar spirit
preserved me in a sphere of energy where
I stayed for a hundred years.
I woke to discover that the balance
preserved by the Avatar had been
destroyed by war.
The air nomads were gone. All but one,
me.
I could no longer run from my
responsibility as the Avatar.
I found allies from every nation.
benders and non-benders.
Katara taught me how to water bend.
Toph trained me in the ways of the
earth benders. Zuko, once my worst
enemy, became my firebending teacher.
Sokka showed me that bravery is the most
important part of being a leader.
We became a family
and together we ended the hundred-year
war.
Then we began the hard work of
rebuilding the world.
For so long, the nation stood apart
alone and we all suffered as a result.
But here on this ancient site, we
created a place where all people are
welcome. Bender and non-bender alike,
working together in peace to build the
future. Though there are still those who
would seek to divide us, we remain
united. As a council representative, I
am honored to be here today celebrating
the anniversary of Republic City and the
opening of Unity Tower, a symbol for all
people.
Look,
it's the Avatar.
Aang, I missed you too, old friend.
Hey,
Katara,
you're hurt.
Take a deep breath
and
exhale.
I've heard the denied are growing in
numbers, but they've never done anything
like this. Attacking the Avatar.
Yeah, they were incredible fighters,
even without bending.
Oops.
Breathe through it.
Be honest. You're enjoying this. Hey,
this is serious. Whatever this map they
took was, if they were willing to kill
the Avatar to get it, what else are they
willing to do?
I don't know.
I'm worried about you. You're spending
more and more time at the Air Temple
alone.
It's how I hold on to my past.
I know how hard this is for you.
When I was attacked,
all I could think about was that
this could be it.
I'm the last Airbender.
If I die, my culture dies with me.
You may be the last Airbender, but
you're not alone.
Aang, none of this would exist without you.
You made the city possible with your
heart and your mind.
Because of you, all of the nations live
here together.
All except mine.
I know. But the people here still need
your protection.
You're an air bender, but you're also
the Avatar.
You're right.
Whoever this Sonum person is, I need to
find out more.
Aang
Avatar Roku,
it is good to see you again. How can I
help you?
In your lifetime, did you ever hear of
an ancient air bender named Sonum?
I have not, but you have many past lives
to call upon. Perhaps one further back
in the Avatar cycle can help you.
Thank you, Avatar Roku.
I'm sorry.
I never heard of
Perhaps earlier.
Not here.
Um, hello.
Is there anyone here?
Hello.
Who calls upon Avatar Seion's vast
wealth of knowledge?
Oh, hello. You look like an Avatar from
a time quite distant from mine. Please,
please tell me about your era. What are
people wearing? Are sandals still a
thing?
Uh, yes.
Why? Why? After so many years, open
toes, seeing someone else's crusty
cuticles.
Disgusting.
Right. Anyway, I have come for your
guidance. You see, I was attacked.
It was not me. Okay. Wasn't me.
I know that. I think it might have
something to do with an air bender named
Sonum.
Sonum? It sounds familiar. Sonum? Where
have I heard that name before? Aha. Son
was the youngest daughter of the owner
of the possum chicken shop at the corner
marketplace. Wait, that was my ex son.
If only she didn't have those humongous
nails. Disgusting.
This is going nowhere.
So,
well, thank you for your time.
I must continue my search.
Oh, Sonum, you are asking about the
legend of the lost avatar.
Sonum was an Avatar. Indeed, she was. She
was the avatar in the golden age of air
benders. Legend said she had a staff
that could channel the vast energy of
the spirit world, granting its keeper
unlimited power.
Is Is that even possible?
We'll never know for sure. Many avatars
have tried to communicate with her, but
they couldn't. She disappeared so
completely that it was as if she never
existed.
And perhaps it's better that way.
Maybe such a staff was too dangerous for
anyone to possess, even the Avatar.
But But that's exactly why I need to
find it. The people who attacked me
discovered a map. It must lead to the
staff. Avatar Seion, please, you have to
tell me where it is.
But legend says that Sonum disappeared
with her staff on the peak of Mount Bou.
Katara, I'm sorry to leave so suddenly,
but I found out what the denied are
after.
Sonum had a staff of immense power, and
in their hands, it could be a
devastating weapon.
They have a head start. There's no time
to waste.
You take Appa and Momo and gather up the
rest of the team. We're going to need
some help.
Next on the agenda, a Fire Nation naval
vessel came into conflict with an
extremist group of non-benders called
the Denied. They've been robbing ancient
sites.
Your Majesty, an urgent message has
arrived from Republic City.
How impertinent. Can't you see Fire Lord
Zuko
Chamberlain?
There's only one person who can send a
message urgent enough to interrupt the
Fire Lord's council.
Is it from the Avatar?
Yes, my lord.
Read it to me. Yes, my lord.
Um,
what are you doing? Read it quickly.
Uh, yeah. Yes. Dear Chamberlain.
Flame of the house ruling the Fire
Nation. I hope the boring Chamberlain
you mentioned in your letters isn't
still annoying you. Anywho, to cut to
the chase, I need your help. Can you
please come immediately? Oh, and don't
forget to bring some firecracker buns.
Allow me to present the Sokka Cycle. Flames
launch you into the sky where you can
drop water bombs on your enemies. Then
skis pop out to help you stick the
landing. Pretty great, right?
Boring.
Why would you need a sled when you can
just water bend?
Oh. Oh. Like me. Like me.
Keep in mind, there are still plenty of
folks like me who can't bend. Why would
Avatar Aang partner with a non-bender?
Why? I'll tell you why. I saved him from
the iceberg. My boomerang flew by his
side while I carried away enemies with
my trusty blade. I even took down the
whole Fire Nation airship Armada.
And on top of all that, I was more
popular than him.
You're such a liar, Sokka.
It's from the Avatar.
Wow.
Really?
Oh, so now you think I'm cool.
All right, metal benders. Let's see if
any of you tenderfoots can at least make
me use my hands.
I'm still the greatest earth bender in
the world.
And I'm bored.
Master Toph, there's a bird on your
head.
And
it looks like it has a message.
Read. Uh, it's from Avatar Aang. He needs
your help. It's the
denied.
Where is he?
Mount Bou.
No, no, no, no.
I love that hat.
Sonum,
could that be you?
Huh?
Who are you?
Heat up
here.
Hey,
Team Avatar to the rescue.
Dang,
you made it.
You couldn't wait a day before running
off to get yourself killed? I thought
you were here looking for a staff. Who's
this guy?
An air bender.
How did he hold up an entire mountain?
His chi is strong like nothing I've ever
felt.
Hey, Avatar, you think this guy beat
your record for longest frozen air
bender?
Yeah. How long do you think he was in
that ice? I don't know. His tattoos look
ancient. He's been in there a long time.
He smells good for an old guy.
E,
what? My senses tell me this guy is
pretty attractive.
Someone else confirmed.
This is serious.
What does attractive even mean?
Just give me a straight confirmation. Is
he attractive?
He's very attractive.
Huh?
What? He is. It's all in the bone
structure.
No.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hey,
you're safe.
Earth.
No, no, no. We're all friends here. It's
okay.
Someone woke up on the wrong side of the
mountain.
Where is she?
Where is Avatar Sonum?
You knew Sonum.
Who are you?
I don't know how to explain it, but
you've been asleep for a long time.
I'm the Avatar now. I'm Aang.
If you're the Avatar,
then
Sonum.
Well, Sonum might be long gone, but on
the bright side, you woke up at the
perfect time. Everyone will be amazed to
see another Airbender. Aang's not the
last one anymore.
What do you mean, last? Oh,
the air nomads.
They've been wiped out.
There's only me.
No.
Sonum's staff. Do you have it? It's our
only hope now.
What do you mean? I thought it was a
weapon.
The staff is no weapon. It is a gift.
With it, Sonum was able to channel the
vast power of the spirit world. It was
this power that allowed Girana to
flourish. The greatest city in the
world, an air nomad utopia where Sonum
presided over a golden age of balance
and where I devoted my life to serving
her. In return, she raised me up and
used her staff to give me, a lowly
non-bender, the power to bend the air.
I was the first, but I would not be the
last.
She filled the skies with air benders,
and we flew by her side, spreading peace
across the world.
Aang, are you okay?
Sonum used the staff to give people
airbending.
If we found it,
I could bring airbending back to the
world.
This is incredible.
There haven't been air benders for over
a hundred years.
This is everything you ever wanted, Aang.
we could heal the greatest atrocity my
nation committed in the war.
This could be the final step to
rebuilding the world.
Not if the denied get there first. They
have the map.
Who are the denied?
A group of violent non-benders. They
They must be after the staff to give
themselves airbending.
Then there's no time to waste. There's
only one place it could be. Ready your
bison. We'll need to travel across the
endless ocean.
On the other side of the world, but
there's nothing out there.
There's an island. The journey will not
be easy, but we can make it.
Then let's get going.
The skies are no place for a water
child.
Water child. Um, I know you just woke up
after thousands of years, but we do
these things together.
Trust me, we're stronger this way.
Welcome to Team Avatar. What's your
name?
Taga. My name is Taga.
Just think of it as a big metal air
bison.
We will travel ancient paths through the
sky,
ones that our people learned by
following the great airbison herds that
long ago taught us airbending.
Air currents known only to us.
Encircling the great sphere of
existence,
allowing us to travel where we wish,
giving us our name, the air nomads.
What's he doing?
He's really feeling that air.
He's navigating by instinct. What if his
instincts are just wrong?
Who needs instincts when you've got
muscles like that?
Or what if his brain is messed up from
being frozen?
Like me?
Uh, no. No, he was frozen for 5,000
years. Okay, you were frozen for what? A
hundred? Okay, that's nothing. Your
brain is fresh. Maybe he is a little
oldfashioned, but look at him. He's so
in tune with his element. He can travel
across the entire ocean with no map, no
instruments.
There's so much I can learn from him.
I'd give anything to be able to see my
airbison again.
And now
to see only one remains.
Aang,
you said our people were wiped out. Yet
you survived.
Oh,
I had just found out I was the Avatar,
but the responsibility,
it was too much.
So, I ran away.
While I was gone, the Fire Nation
attacked.
They were looking for me.
If if I'd just been there,
Sonum would say, "Air nomads are formed
from the mist. We walk the world for a
moment in time, then we return to the
eternal wind."
Something tells me that
we carry the same weight, a grief no one
else could possibly comprehend. But you
and I can heal the past. Let me show you
how powerful our element can be when
airbenders work together.
What are you doing?
This is how Sonum taught me. Feel the
energy that tethers us.
The bond between us. Can you feel it?
Use it.
This is amazing.
Woohoo! Oh yeah! Human boomerang!
He's actually flying.
So are we.
Wa! That's my best friend. That's my
best friend.
No, you throw me.
I had no idea this was possible.
This is only the beginning.
I can't believe it. Airbenders will fill
the sky again.
We have been given a great gift. The
chance to redeem ourselves. You are
destined to find me on that mountain.
Aang.
How did you end up there?
The earthbenders had attacked Girana.
Sonum and I fought fearlessly side by
side. We drove them back to Mount Bou,
and that's the last I remember.
She must have saved your life. Only an
Avatar could have put you in that
sphere.
Aang,
can I ask you something?
Of course.
If the Fire Nation destroyed the Air
Nomads,
how can you suffer the presence of the
Fire Lord?
Zuko is a friend and an ally. He turned
against his own father to help me end
the war.
Yet he wears the crown himself. Now fire
by its nature burns. Aang our kind have
always suffered at the hands of the
other elements.
That's why we built Republic City to
show the world that if we listen to each
other, we can all live together in
peace.
And once we bring back air benders,
it'll be complete.
When everyone stuck to their own, the
whole world was nearly torn apart. And
besides, Katara, Sokka, Zuko, Toph,
they're my family now.
I want to live in a world where we can
all be together.
You remind me so much of Sonum.
It's the Avatar. And this time he's got
his friends with them.
That's the Fire Lord's airship. How'd
they get ahead of us? They don't even
have the map.
We can't risk him getting to the staff
first. Kill him. But he spared our
lives. And how many countless were
killed in the hundred years waiting for
his return? Where was he when your
family was wiped out? If we want
anything to change, we need what the
Benders have. Power.
Fire.
It's the denied.
Oh, we are definitely under attack.
Let us spread.
Is he crushing the ship?
Taga,
stop.
We're here.
The immortal storm.
Oh no.
There has to be another way around.
No. Together, you and I can clear a path
for the ship. But we have to go now.
Hey, trust me.
Maybe now's a good time to turn back.
I don't think that's an option anymore.
Where are they going?
The engine's out. We're losing air
pressure.
Oh, come with me. What about me? Take
the wheel.
What? I've only ever crashed Fire Nation
airships.
Okay, let's see. Here's our rudder. This
is the elevator. There's our ballast.
And there's the giant tornado that's
going to kill us all.
Follow my lead.
Work with me. Just like I showed you, we
can harness.
Yes, that's it. Keep going.
Got it.
Zuko. Zuko. Aang and Taga are destroying
tornadoes, but there's too many and
they're everywhere. Just steer the ship.
Don't lose Aang
It's not that easy, especially when
everything is sideways. Okay. Left.
I did it.
Right.
Oh no, we're falling behind.
I'm losing sight of them. We have to go
back.
Trust in your friends. They won't make
it if we don't clear a path.
Zuko, we're going to crash into the sea.
When I give you the signal, pull the
lever next to the wheel.
We're going to crash. We're going to
crash. Katara.
Give me the signal. Give me the signal.
Sokka now. Here we go.
Katara, we did it.
What were you thinking?
I was clearing the tornadoes to make a
path.
The ship almost crashed, Aang. We could
have died. And what if you got yourself
killed? You're the Avatar. This is too
risky. We need to turn back now.
No, we're almost there. We just need to
get to the eye of the storm.
Hey, no. This is too dangerous.
The staff is out there. The denied are
after it.
Do you really believe that they could
make it through the storm?
We're nearly there. That staff can bring
back my people.
I understand how much you want that.
You don't understand. None of you do.
Aang,
we push forward.
If we generate enough air, we can push
our way through.
We're alive. We made it through. Thank
you, Taga.
It was you, Aang. We're here because of
you.
Yeah, we're having a good time, too. You
could have told us we were flying into
the immortal storm.
I know it was dangerous, but we had to
risk it.
We don't remember when we took a vote on
that.
There wasn't time. I had to make a call.
Friends, please don't blame Aang. This is
all my fault. I knew this would be
difficult, but Aang believed in your
strength as a team, and I'm honored to
be a part of it.
I forgive you, Taga.
Everyone, look,
these islands, they were lion turtles.
Whoa,
it's beautiful.
Long before my time, the lion turtles
granted the gift of bending to humans.
These are their final resting grounds.
This is where Sonum came to learn their
ways.
I am certain that she left her staff
here.
Where should we start looking?
Aang, you must connect with her.
But no one can connect with Sonum. The
spiritual power of the Lion Turtles is
still concentrated here. Let it guide
you. We'll set out immediately.
Actually, Taga, we could really use your
help here. If the Denied are close
behind, we need to be ready.
Yeah, and we're going to need more than
Toph's metal bending to fix this.
My bending got us through that storm.
What did you do?
Steered with his feet.
Repairs can wait. Aang needs me.
Taga, please stay and help my friends.
I'll be okay on my own.
As you wish. We will begin repairs for
our voyage home.
Everyone,
I know I've asked a lot of you on this
journey, but we're about to accomplish
something that will change the world.
I got to go.
Let it guide you.
Son,
this is turning out to be a nice little
vacation.
Aside from all the people trying to kill
us and the tornadoes.
Um, we're supposed to be fixing the
ship.
You're doing great, buddy.
Has anyone seen Taga?
Yes, we've all seen Taga. He's so
gorgeous. Jeez, I get it. Oh, I see what
you mean. He wandered off that way. No,
maybe that way.
Taga,
where are you going?
Aang needs to be protected.
I agree.
I know my ways may seem unusual to you,
but I assure you everything I do, I do
for Aang
or for the staff.
You have no idea all that we've lost.
You've never known a world with
airbenders.
I know Aang may be the last of his kind,
but he's the reason this world knows
peace.
His values as an air nomad have brought
balance to chaos.
It's because of Aang that the water tribes,
earth kingdom, and fire nation now work
together, striving for harmony. A peace
we once thought unattainable.
You speak of peace. There will never be
peace among the elements. There never
was. Your precious Republic City is
built on lies.
It's built on hope. Do you have hope,
Taga?
Saving my people requires more than just
hope. It requires sacrifice.
I saw you try to crush the Denied's
airship. You were ready to kill them.
I know what kind of air bender Aang is.
But what kind of air bender are you?
Aang did well getting us here. There is
great strength in him, but weakness as
well.
Weakness.
Yes. You
What the hog monkey?
No,
he trusted you.
the
Huh?
Hold up.
Move.
Brother
Taga, it's real.
We can finally bring back air bending.
Let's go tell the others.
We can do this. Me and you.
I can't do this without my friends.
Earth killed my people. Fire killed
yours. The staff is the only way we can
create a new air empire. One capable of
defending itself.
No. We can build a new future, Taga. But
it has to be for everyone.
The staff doesn't belong to everyone. It
belongs to us.
What? What have you done?
As long as they were around, you'd
always put them ahead of our people.
Don't you see? This is how we redeem
ourselves. It doesn't matter that you
ran, as long as you stand with me
now.
Hey, listen to me. This is the only way.
You're a traitor to your own. Just like
Sonum.
I wanted to do this with you by my side.
But if I must build the new air empire
alone,
so be it.
There's no way in. We have to turn back.
No, we keep trying to push through.
Sonum's staff,
denied.
The Avatar is dead. If you wish to build
a new world where you have the power, I
can give it to you.
Aang! Katara,
they're gone. It's all my fault.
It's always been my fault. Ever since I
ran away,
no Avatar has ever fallen into such
shame as to join me here in my sorrow.
Why do you grieve so friend?
Avatar Sonum
Taga murdered my friends and now he has
a staff.
Taga? No. No. I I stopped him. I hid the
staff. What have you done?
You're the one who gave him air bending.
How could you give power to a monster?
The Taga I gave bending to was a
different man.
It was a different time.
The Airbenders were the peacekeepers of
the four elements. We used our power to
mediate all conflict with nonviolence.
But we were the fewest in numbers.
For many years, we existed in a
beautiful balance of great prosperity.
But the world began to shift. The
Earthbenders formed their own kingdom,
separating from the other elemental
tribes. The balance of the world was at
risk. It was my duty to act.
So, I learned how to channel the energy
of the spirit world just as the Lion
Turtles did, to give people the power of
airbending.
My most devout pupil, Taga, was the
first to receive it.
I sent my new peacekeepers out to help
calm the growing unrest,
but they were not prepared for the
brutality of the new Earth Kingdom.
Taga watched as his brothers and sisters
were all slaughtered.
His heart darkened by the violence of
war. He now saw everyone who wasn't an
air nomad as the enemy.
Taga begged me to use the staff to
create an army and to kill all who would
do us harm. I refused,
so he stole it.
When he connected the staff to the
temple, his energy was so corrupted by
grief and rage that the power of the
spirit world consumed him.
Taga became something more than human,
too powerful to kill. It took all my
energy to finally trap him high above
the clouds where no one would find him.
I reclaimed the staff, but I was fatally
wounded.
Before the Earth Kingdom could invade
Girana, I sent the remaining air nomads
into the mountains.
And I hid my temple in the spirit world
where no one could access its power.
And then I locked the staff away where
only the Avatar could find it.
I died hoping that one day another
Avatar would create more air benders and
restore balance to this world. And that
Avatar is you, Aang. You have to get my
staff before Taga connects it to the
temple. There's still time. Don't let my
regret become yours.
My friends and I fought hard for this
peace.
I won't let him start another war. Help
me find a way back.
Sonum,
what's happening?
No. No. Please. I have to fix this. This
can't be it. I can't die yet. Please,
not yet. No. Katara.
Come on, Aang. Come on, Aang. Hold on.
Aang, Katara,
I was so worried.
Aang, Sokka,
I knew you'd pull through, buddy. Hey,
Aang. Zuko. Momo,
welcome back, Twinkletoes.
Toph. You're okay. I I thought you were
all dead. We were. But Katara saved us.
The spiritual power of these waters
strengthened my healing abilities.
You're incredible.
Where's Appa?
Taga must have taken him.
I'm sorry.
No.
I can't believe I trusted him.
We'll get through this.
So, let me get this straight. He's
pulling Sonum's temple out of the spirit
world to gain unlimited power. And let
me guess, you want us to stop him?
Sure. Only problem is your air bro
crushed our ship and stole your bison.
Also, there's a massive typhoon
surrounding us.
I don't say this very often, but Sokka's
right.
Thank you.
Yep. We're stuck. And there aren't
enough lion turtles for all of us to
have our own island. So, I'm calling
this one. I'm naming him Snappy.
Aang, Snappy is the best one.
I know.
We may not know where Taga is, but we
know what he's looking for is in the
spirit world. And lucky for us, we're
stuck in the most spiritually charged
place on the planet. So, I may be able
to open a portal to get us there if I
can summon an old friend.
Wow,
the ocean spirit.
This portal smells an awful lot like the
fish market.
I'm going to go check on Snappy. Face
your death with honor.
I'm sorry. I know I got us into this,
but I promise you I'll fix it.
We'll fix it
together.
We're going to die. We're going to die.
What? Where's my power pony?
Uh, were my hands always this small?
It's baby Toph! Baby Toph!
What the hog monkey? Oh, people.
Grand,
that's your sister, you mean head. Give
me to There. There. Toph.
No, Zuko. What happened to your
beautiful face? You look like a dried
sea squid.
No, Zuko.
What's going on here?
Spirit world is out of balance.
And so are we.
That's got to be Taga.
Oh no, he's pulling Sonum's temple into
our world. We're running out of time.
Pretty good landing.
Whoa, humans. I love humans. Two
brothers, their little sister, as an
elderly couple. They look like
a couple.
Whoa. Looks like I touched a nerve.
Look at this one. Hello.
Talk. No. Bad talk.
We don't bite strangers.
Great spirit. Excuse me. Did you just
come from that temple in the sky?
I certainly did.
It was my favorite hidey-hole until that
dark, yucky energy started corrupting
this whole place.
Please, we need your help getting up
there. It's my duty to stop this. I'm
the Avatar.
Oo,
Let me have a squeeze you.
Okay. Now, with this eye and this eye.
Mhm. And this side. Oh, don't forget
this. Hey,
can we hurry it up?
Sniff.
Oh, that's the real Avatar right there. Yes,
it is. Oh, yes. Yes, yes, yes, yes. It
appears the universe has brought us
together for a very important mission.
To flee and be alive.
Wait, come back. We're going the wrong
way. Stop. Please, great spirit. Both of
our worlds are in danger.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no. I am not
going back up there.
Well, when you put it like that, it does
make more sense.
Upon reflection, I've decided I shall
help you and your human friends.
What did he say?
Nice work, Momo.
All right, in you go.
By the way, no eating anything you find
in my teeth as I'm saving that for
later. Ready, set, get ready and one and
two. And do you know what to do?
I know we haven't known each other very
long, but I love you. You don't have to
say it back.
Hey, you got your hair back.
Why are my eyes teary? Was I crying?
No way. Look.
What? What is it?
It's Republic City.
We can't let him destroy everything
we've built.
We won't.
Boomerang.
Give me the staff, Taga.
I see. I underestimated you, Avatar.
Your friends are stronger than I
thought. But you're too late.
They're denied.
You see, I did what you wanted, Aang. I
returned airbending to the world.
What's the plan?
We'll deal with the denied. You have to
get the staff.
I will rebuild Girana in the ruins of
our enemies, just as they did on ours. A
new air empire will rise. Kill them all.
We have to get these people out of here.
Oh yeah,
give it to me.
This isn't the way we can use the staff
to bring back balance, peace.
You care so much about your ideal that
you'd let your people die.
I will do anything to make sure they
survive.
My cabbages. My cabbages.
My cabbages.
My cabbage.
Don't do this. You have the power now.
You can decide how to use it.
I'm not like you. The world hasn't been
good to me.
The world is what we make it. Get away
from her.
Taga, stop.
You betrayed me. You betray our culture.
I gave you every chance to see the
truth.
Shouldn't you be in the Fire Nation?
I'm fighting for the peace of all
nations.
Big talk from someone who sits on a
throne built on a century of war.
I'm still the greatest earth bender in
the world.
Oh no, I'm out of water.
We got you.
And there's no Avatar here to save you.
Sokka Cycle.
Let's see if your fancy new bending can
beat some good old non-bending knowhow.
You just got denied.
Let's go.
Good luck saving your city.
We have to save as many people as we
can.
I know your pain. I know what you've
been through.
You don't know.
I watched as all of my brothers and
sisters were slaughtered when the Fire
Nation burned the Air Nomads to ash.
Where were you?
You ran.
Aang
no.
The full power of the spirit world flows
through me.
strength looks like.
You should have run away like you did
all those years ago, little Avatar.
I
won't run.
Then at least you'll die knowing you're
not the last airbender.
Oh my god.
Oh no.
We could have been brothers. We could
have done this together. It didn't have
to end like this.
Zang, he's got the staff.
Yeah, kick his butt, Mega Aang.
No, something's wrong. The power is
corrupting him.
I dreamt of bringing the air nomads back
to the world as peacekeepers. They could
have been a beacon of light for the
world to follow. But you ruined it. You
twisted my dream into a nightmare.
Finally, you have the power the air
nomads need. Maybe there is hope for you
after all.
Do it. Use the staff. Show me you have
the strength to bring our people back.
Do it.
Aang
You will do so many great things as the
Avatar, but you must be prepared to do
what frightens you the most.
Your people, your home. We are always
with you.
No
No, my power.
No.
You fool. Why? Why did you break it? We
could have fixed everything.
We can't erase the pain of the past.
We couldn't save them.
But it's our duty to protect our people.
Not at the cost of betraying everything
they stood for.
No.
It's time to let go.
You have to forgive yourself.
I have to forgive myself, too.
Air nomads are born from the mist.
We walk the world for a moment in time.
Then we return
to the eternal wind.
Hey.
Hey,
seriously, you do realize you're
falling, right? Hey, if you ever get
tired of relying on Appa, I could hook
you up with one of these babies.
I'll give you the best friend discount.
I don't know if airbending will ever
return.
But I know now that the true power of
the air nomads was never their bending.
It was their values.
And that's a power I can pass on to
others.
Avatar Aang, you are the true embodiment
of the Air Nomads.
Thank you for giving up the power that I
could not.
You give me hope for the future of our
culture.
It's amazing, isn't it? The first new
air temple in centuries.
Republic City is finally complete.
A city for all nations, just like you
promised.
I never could have done this without
you, Katara.
Hey everybody. Sorry I kept you all
waiting. Are you ready for our big trip?
As my new acolytes, you'll be helping me
preserve our culture for future
generations.
So, who wants to search for artifacts at
an ancient abandoned temple?
Yay. I'm only going to make sure you
don't try to release another evil old
airbender.
Yeah, I'm done with bad boys.
Avatar Sonum told me about this place.
So, it's very possible that no one's
been here in hundreds of years.
Oh, is this an air bender relic?
I think that's just a rock, but I love
the enthusiasm.
Aang
keep your eyes open. You never know what
we might discover here.
I thought they were extinct.
I can't believe it. The original
Airbenders.
Can I have one?
Ha. You give
Oh yeah.
Oh.
Oh
yeah. Oh.
My
Bless our
Glory.
Oh,
All the
endless
praise.